<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>The online space of - Jason Kenyon</title>
    <link href="https://romantic-engelbart-c180b4.netlify.com" />
    <link type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" href="https://romantic-engelbart-c180b4.netlify.com/blog/feed.atom" />
    <updated>2020-02-12T03:34:20+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://romantic-engelbart-c180b4.netlify.com/blog/feed.atom</id>
    <author>
        <name>Jason Kenyon</name>
    </author>
                <entry>
    <id>https://romantic-engelbart-c180b4.netlify.com/blog/stop-being-a-boss-be-a-leader</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://romantic-engelbart-c180b4.netlify.com/blog/stop-being-a-boss-be-a-leader" />
    <title>Stop being a boss, be a leader</title>
    <published>2020-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Jason Kenyon</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">So wait, you are saying that I shouldn&#039;t be a boss?  What do you even mean by this?  Absolutely! Being a leader is being a boss but with different leadership skills.  You aren&#039;t bossing or demanding, or pointing fingers.  A boss uses&#039; words such as I,......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <h3>Being a Leader is Better Than a Boss</h3>

<p>So wait, you are saying that I shouldn't be a boss?  What do you even mean by this?  Absolutely! Being a leader is being a boss but with different leadership skills.  You aren't bossing or demanding, or pointing fingers.  A boss uses' words such as I, me, myself...</p>

<p>A leader will use words such as we, us, our, team.   You still a boss can't be a boss without people under them, but a boss also will have issues with keeping people under them, whereas a leader will stay.</p>

<blockquote>
  <h4>People don't leave companies they leave BOSSES.</h4>
</blockquote>

<h3>Why You Should Strive To Be a Leader</h3>

<p>Being a leader is so much more important than being a friend, you challenge yourself to teach, encourage, and bring people out of their comfort zone.  You take the time to teach them and offer a helping hand when things get rough.  A boss is just someone that will push paper, and do what is best for them, and not what's best for them.</p>

<p>Is being a boss a bad thing? That depends on how you take your title of being a boss.  While I'm a supervisor, and technically I'm the boss of many people under me, I don't refer to myself as their boss but their leader.</p>

<p>You see each person that is under me is someone, and that someone has their weaknesses and strengths; it is my job to discover those weaknesses and strengths and encourage them to continue to grow as a person and employee within the company.</p>

<p>At the end, when you are a leader you are ensuring that the company will be successful because more and more people will stay with that company.  People don't get tired of the company, they get tired of their bosses, and how they are treated by them.</p>

<p>What struck me and motivated me to even write this post, was a simple YouTube Video; The video creator makes a great point and asks a great question.</p>

<blockquote>
  <h4>Sir, ask yourself this question.  But, have you ever heard of a World Boss?</h4>
</blockquote>

<p>I encourage anyone that is reading this to take the time and watch it, the message in the video is powerful, encouraging, and something that we as leaders or even employees should follow.  You can find that video at <strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LrVNTZ6ORm8">Boss vs Employee (2020) </a></strong></p>

<h3>Dealing with Performance Management</h3>

<p>So, of course, this will bring the topics of so we shouldn't issue performance management, and be our employees' friends.  The answer to this is simple, Definitely Not!   Performance management is in place to provide that feedback to the employee, to coach and develop them.</p>

<p>Though dealing with performance management, as a leader the employee will know what is coming and how they got there.  As you took the time to teach, and offer a hand to help them out.  By this time you should have had conversations and understand what that employee is struggling with. It is at this time, that they are at a crossroad, and will have to choose their path.   On one end of that path is yourself, as a leader holding out your hand to improve and offer your guidance to your employee, and on the other is an empty road with no street lights and a path of uncertainty.</p>

<blockquote>
  <p><strong><em>The Opinions Expressed In This Post Are My Own and How I Feel and View Things in a Postion That I am In.</em></strong></p>
</blockquote>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://romantic-engelbart-c180b4.netlify.com/blog/first-post-on-the-blog</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://romantic-engelbart-c180b4.netlify.com/blog/first-post-on-the-blog" />
    <title>First post on the blog</title>
    <published>2020-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Jason Kenyon</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">Hi, I&#039;m Jason!  Welcome to my first blog post.

Recently, blogs have become a big source and wealth of knowledge.  I desired to jump on this and provide the wealth of knowledge that I have also come across and experienced, between PHP, MySQL,......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>Hi, I'm Jason!  Welcome to my first blog post.</p>

<p>Recently, blogs have become a big source and wealth of knowledge.  I desired to jump on this and provide the wealth of knowledge that I have also come across and experienced, between PHP, MySQL, Applications that I use, and how I am not a boss but a leader for the company I work for.</p>

<p>So welcome to my new website.  I plan on blogging about programming, and what I've learned sifting through the Laravel community in the dark.  I'm also setting up a place to allow me to provide and share tutorials, overall life posts, including how I am a supervisor who doesn't refer to myself as a boss, simply as a leader.</p>

<p>So if you're ready? We will go ahead and jump into it.  I wanted to start my first post by providing a bit of information on what I built the website on and a bit more about myself.</p>

<p>Though that is always the hard part right, what should I start with?  I guess I will provide a bit more information about myself so that you know who is writing.</p>

<h3>A Bit More About Jason</h3>

<p>Honestly, I'm just a simple man that enjoys learning new things and teaching.  I live in <strong>Newport News, Virginia</strong>; with my lovely wife, who just so happens to also run a business, <a href="https://preciousmemories.photography">PreciousMemories Photography</a>.  Running this with her has truly been an eye-opening experience, I guess I didn't see how much work is involved in trying to build and run a company.</p>

<p>Between the two of us, we have 6 kids together.  I have 3 girls, and 2 boys, that I couldn't be more proud of.  I'm also a <em>stepfather</em> of her son, but at the end of the day, do we need to put <em>stepfather</em> into something?  I have always felt that blood doesn't define you as a family, but the love and connection that you have with each other.</p>

<h3>The Road to Static Site Generators that Just Didn't Work Out.</h3>

<p>Okay, okay, I get it you are ready for the gears that run the website. Well, I started off coding the website in a variety of things.  One of which I started to write it in <a href="https://laravel.com">Laravel</a>, simply because it is a PHP framework that I simply love, and want to use it on every project.  Though of course, we all know that each project/site has it's own requirements and building it with <a href="https://laravel.com">Laravel</a> was just going to be overkill.</p>

<p>So I started a hunt of things, I didn't want to use WordPress.  It's a good solid blogging platform, though I feel that their vision has gone away from being just that, a blogging platform to a full-blown CMS.  It tries hard to be a CMS, and honestly, the core isn't too grave? My issue is the plugins and themes that you can get for it, failure of patching things, and always trying to keep things updated.  I wanted something that was going to be fast, simple and easy to update.</p>

<p>Static sites here I come... So I went on the look for finding the best static site generator that I could find.  Though we know this is again a user preference.  I started looking at and working with <a href="https://www.gatsbyjs.org/">Gatsby</a>, it was solid and felt great using it.  I started looking at that and using Contentful as the backend after I found a post on <a href="https://medium.com/@ryanwiemer/gatsby-and-the-jam-stack-91e31508f364">Medium</a> from <a href="https://medium.com/@ryanwiemer">Ryan Wiemer</a>.</p>

<p>After a couple of weeks of development, it just felt <strong>over-complicated</strong> to what I was trying to do, and I thought about upkeep, do I want to rely that much on javascript?  Well, then I found <a href="https://gridsome.org/">Gridsome</a>, <em>yes okay I know it is also done on Javascript and built using <strong>Vuejs</strong> instead of <strong>Reactjs</strong>.</em></p>

<p>So I started playing with <a href="https://gridsome.org/">Gridsome</a>, and honestly, to be quite frank I truly <strong>loved</strong> it more than <strong>Gatsby</strong>, it was more of something that I knew and was familiar with, after all, I come from the Laravel community where <a href="https://vuejs.org/">Vuejs</a> is a big player.</p>

<p>Everything was coming together, and I completed it and launched it on Netlify with a backend, though after a while it still felt like something was missing or I was <strong>overdoing</strong> it with the <em>javascript</em>.  So I had begun the hunt once again for something that would work out.</p>

<h3>Jigsaw by TightenCo That Lead a Clear Path</h3>

<p>I finally came across and landed on <a href="https://jigsaw.tighten.co/">Jigsaw</a>, by TigtenCo.  Honestly, I couldn't be happier with how things worked out with the system, they have an amazing <a href="https://github.com/tightenco/jigsaw-blog-template">blog template</a> to start from, which to be honest that is what is being used right now with just edits to make it my style.</p>

<p>All the blog posts are all done and wrote in Markdown, heck even my <a href="https://jasonkenyon.me/uses">uses</a> page is done in Markdown, which is just great and powerful enough so that I don't have to write a single more line of HTML.   The CSS framework being used is none other than TailwindCSS.</p>

<p>Though if I have to really be honest what I love the most about <strong>Jigaw</strong>;  it would really have to boil down to just being able to use <a href="https://laravel.com/docs/master/blade">Laravel's blade</a> templating.</p>

<p>With the duo pack that is running now, I just feel overly pleased with how things have come together.  I will honestly continue to use <strong>Jigsaw</strong> because it is just dead simple, and easy to use and makes making static websites a breeze.</p>

<p>Overall, I'm still learning more and more about <strong>Jigsaw</strong>, I will continue to blog about my experience with <strong>Jigsaw</strong>, and post new updates on things that I'm working on, and any releases or new information that I think everyone will enjoy.</p>

<p>Until next time, have a good day/week, and stay searching, learning and getting it!</p>
    ]]></content>
</entry>
    </feed>
