<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>The online space of - Jason Kenyon</title>
    <link href="https://jasonkenyon.me" />
    <link type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" href="https://jasonkenyon.me/blog/feed.atom" />
    <updated>2020-02-13T21:56:45+00:00</updated>
    <id>https://jasonkenyon.me/blog/feed.atom</id>
    <author>
        <name>Jason Kenyon</name>
    </author>
                <entry>
    <id>https://jasonkenyon.me/blog/stop-being-a-boss-be-a-leader</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://jasonkenyon.me/blog/stop-being-a-boss-be-a-leader" />
    <title>Stop being a boss, be a leader</title>
    <published>2020-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Jason Kenyon</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">So wait, you are saying that I shouldn&#039;t be a boss? What do you even mean by this? Being a leader is being a boss but with diverse leadership practices. 
You aren&#039;t bossing or commanding, neither pointing fingers. A boss uses words such as I, me,......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <h3>Being a Leader is Better Than a Boss</h3>
<p>So wait, you are saying that I shouldn't be a boss? What do you even mean by this? Being a leader is being a boss but with diverse leadership practices. </p>
<p>You aren't bossing or commanding, neither pointing fingers. A boss uses words such as I, me, myself... </p>
<p>A leader will use words such as we, us. A boss will have issues with keeping people under them. Where a leader will have people stay, thrive, gain respect for those below them. </p>
<blockquote>
<h4>Employees don't drop companies they leave managers/supervisors.</h4>
</blockquote>
<h3>Why You Should Strive To Be a Leader</h3>
<p>Being a leader is so much more influential than being a boss! You challenge yourself to teach, encourage, guide people out of their comfort zone. You take the time to develop them and offer a helping hand when things get rocky. A boss is someone that will push paper and do what is best for them, moreover not necessarily what is suitable for the morale of the company. </p>
<p>Is being a boss a bad thing? This depends on how you take your power of being a boss. While I'm a supervisor, I'm the supervisor of various people under me. However, I don't relate to myself as their boss but as their leader. </p>
<p>You see each person that is under me is someone! That someone has vulnerabilities and strengths. It is my responsibility to discover these vulnerabilities and strengths. Help them grow as a person, and as an employee within the organization. </p>
<p>At the end, when you are a leader you are guaranteeing that the company will be thriving because more people will stay. People don't get frustrated by the company, they get weary of their bosses, and how they get treated. </p>
<p>What prompted me to even write this post. Was a inspring YouTube video, the video creator makes a great point and asks a great question.</p>
<blockquote>
<h4>Sir, ask yourself this question... Have you ever heard of a &quot;World Boss&quot;?</h4>
</blockquote>
<p>I recommend anyone that is reading this to take the time and watch the video. The message in the video is powerful, encouraging.</p>
<p>Something that we as leaders or even employees should follow. You can find that video at <strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LrVNTZ6ORm8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Boss vs Employee (2020) </a></strong></p>
<h3>Dealing with Performance Management</h3>
<p>So, this will bring the subjects of so we shouldn't issue performance administration. Furthermore, be our employees' friends. The answer to this is simple!</p>
<p>Performance management is in place to provide that feedback to the employee. To coach and develop them. An employee will thrive for feedback if provided with care.</p>
<p>As a leader, you have to find the balance of providing it. By the time performance management is needed. The employee should know what you have done to help them.</p>
<p>They will also see and understand that performance management is coming. As you took the time to develop and extend a hand to help them out. </p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong><em>The Opinions Expressed In This Post Are My Own and How I View Things in a Position That I am In.</em></strong></p>
</blockquote>    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>https://jasonkenyon.me/blog/first-post-on-the-blog</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="https://jasonkenyon.me/blog/first-post-on-the-blog" />
    <title>First post on the blog</title>
    <published>2020-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Jason Kenyon</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">Hi, I&#039;m Jason! Welcome to my first blog post.
Recently, blogs have become a high source and wealth of information. I craved to jump on this and provide the resources of information. That I have also come across and experienced. Within PHP, MySQL,......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>Hi, I'm Jason! Welcome to my first blog post.</p>
<p>Recently, blogs have become a high source and wealth of information. I craved to jump on this and provide the resources of information. That I have also come across and experienced. Within PHP, MySQL, Applications that I use, and how I am not a boss but a leader for the organization I work for. </p>
<p>So, welcome to my brand-new website. I intend on blogging about programming, life; and what else may come to mind. </p>
<p>I also want to write about what I've learned from the Laravel community. I'm also establishing a place to allow me to provide and yield tutorial life posts.</p>
<p>So if you're ready; we will go ahead and dive into it. I wanted to start my first post by providing information on what I made the website on.</p>
<p>I also figured that it was a good time to give readers that will visit my site, a bit more information about me. It allows you to know who is behind the scenes and writing these blog posts.</p>
<p>Though that is always the troublesome part right... What should I start with? I guess I will present a bit more information about myself so that you know who is writing these blog posts.</p>
<h3>A Bit More About Jason</h3>
<p>I'm an uncomplicated man that appreciates learning new things and teaching. I live in <strong>Newport News, Virginia</strong>. With my beautiful wife, who happens to also run her own business. <a href="https://preciousmemories.photography" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PreciousMemories Photography</a>.</p>
<p>Running the business with her has been an eye-opening adventure! I didn't understand how much work is involved in trying to create and run a business.</p>
<p>Between the two of us, we have 6 kids together. I have 3 girls, and 2 boys, that I couldn't be more proud of. I'm also a <em>stepfather</em> of her son but at the end of the day... </p>
<p>Do we need to put <em>stepfather</em> into something? I have always thought that blood doesn't define your family. The love and connection that you have with each other.</p>
<h3>The Road to Static Site Generators that Didn't Work Out.</h3>
<p>Okay, okay, I get it you are ready for the nuts and bolts that run this website. Well, I started off coding the website in a variety of things. One of which I started to write it in was <a href="https://laravel.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Laravel</a>. It is a PHP framework that I completely enjoy, and want to use it on every project. </p>
<p>Though of course, we all know that each project/site has its requirements. Building it with <a href="https://laravel.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Laravel</a> was completely going to be overkill. </p>
<p>I didn't want to use WordPress. It's a good firm blogging platform, though their vision has gone away from being just that. A blogging platform to a full-blown CMS.</p>
<p>It tries too hard to be a CMS, and honestly, the core isn't too bad? (joke attended) The issue is plugins and themes that you can get for it. Neglecting to patch things, and always trying to keep plugins/themes updated.</p>
<p>People also tend to overdo it with the plugins, making their website slow. (Not that WordPress by default isn't slow already...) I wanted something that was going to be fast, simple and easy to update.</p>
<p>Static sites here I come! So I went on the look for finding the most suitable static site generator that I could find. Though we know this is a user preference. </p>
<p>I started working with <a href="https://www.gatsbyjs.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gatsby</a>, it was solid and felt great.  I was also using Contentful as the backend after I found a post on <a href="https://medium.com/@ryanwiemer/gatsby-and-the-jam-stack-91e31508f364" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Medium</a> from <a href="https://medium.com/@ryanwiemer" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Ryan Wiemer</a>.</p>
<p>After a couple of weeks of development; it just felt <strong>overly-complicated</strong>... I thought about maintenance, do I want to rely that much on javascript? </p>
<p>Well, I then found <a href="https://gridsome.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gridsome</a>, <em>yes okay I know it is also javascript and built using <strong>Vuejs</strong> rather than <strong>Reactjs</strong>.</em></p>
<p>So I started playing with <a href="https://gridsome.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gridsome</a>, and naturally, to be quite straightforward I truly <strong>preferred</strong> it over <strong>Gatsby</strong>. </p>
<p>It was more of something that I knew and was familiar with. After all, I come from the Laravel community where <a href="https://vuejs.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Vuejs</a> is a prominent player. </p>
<p>Everything was coming together, and I completed and launched the site with Netlify. Though after a while it still felt like something was yearning or I was <strong>overdoing</strong> it with <em>javascript</em>. So I had begun the hunt once again for something that may work out better.</p>
<h3>Jigsaw by TightenCo That Lead a Clear Path</h3>
<p>I ultimately came across and settled on <a href="https://jigsaw.tighten.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jigsaw</a>, by TigtenCo. Truly, I couldn't be more satisfied with how things worked out. They have a marvelous <a href="https://github.com/tightenco/jigsaw-blog-template" target="_blank" rel="noopener">blog template</a> to start from. Which is being used right now with just edits to make it my style, on this very website! </p>
<p>All the blog posts are all done and wrote in Markdown, heck even my <a href="https://jasonkenyon.me/uses" target="_blank" rel="noopener">uses</a> page is done in Markdown! Which is just exceptional and robust enough so that I don't have to write a single line more of HTML. </p>
<p>The CSS framework used is none other than <a href="https://tailwindcss.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TailwindCSS</a>. Which if you have not heard of it, or even tried it. I can't encourage you enough to, just stop reading this and try it out! It is an astounding CSS framework. </p>
<blockquote>
<p>Tailwind is different.</p>
<p>Instead of opinionated predesigned components, Tailwind provides low-level utility classes that let you build completely custom designs without ever leaving your HTML.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Though if I have to be realistic about what I prefer the greatest about <strong>Jigsaw</strong>; it would have to boil down to just being able to use <a href="https://laravel.com/docs/master/blade" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Laravel's blade</a> templating. </p>
<p>With the duo pack that is running now, I just feel overly satisfied with how things have come together. I will honestly continue to use <strong>Jigsaw</strong>. It is just dead simple, and easy to use and makes making static websites a breeze.</p>
<p>Overall, I'm still learning more and more about <strong>Jigsaw</strong>. I will continue to blog about my adventure with it and post new updates on things that I'm working on. Any releases or new information that I think everyone will enjoy.</p>
<p>Until next time, have a good day/week, and stay searching, learning and getting it!</p>    ]]></content>
</entry>
    </feed>
