<?xml version="1.0"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
    <title>The online space of - Jason Kenyon</title>
    <link href="" />
    <link type="application/atom+xml" rel="self" href="/blog/feed.atom" />
    <updated>2020-11-28T05:26:38+00:00</updated>
    <id>/blog/feed.atom</id>
    <author>
        <name>Jason Kenyon</name>
    </author>
                <entry>
    <id>/blog/verifying-requests-from-slack</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="/blog/verifying-requests-from-slack" />
    <title>Verifying Requests from Slack</title>
    <published>2020-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-03-07T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Jason Kenyon</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">Recently, I have been developing and building more and more things for Slack. More so, it was updating some apps that I created with just PHP without a framework, to use Laravel and make it a bit more expandable. I also undertook a complete code base......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>Recently, I have been developing and building more and more things for <em>Slack</em>. More so, it was updating some apps that I created with just PHP without a framework, to use Laravel and make it a bit more expandable. I also undertook a complete code base update, so that the application itself wasn't using the Dialogs but instead using their new Modals.</p>
<h2>The Big Ol' Rookie Mistake...</h2>
<p>Then this got me to thinking and wondering, I know that there is a Signing Secret key; though to be 100% honest, I never gave it considerable thought or pursued looking into what this Signing Secret was all about. I'll admit this was a big rookie mistake, but something that I learned from and figured I would share with anyone else.</p>
<p>So what exactly is this Signing Secret key? The Signing Secret key is to be used in conjunction with verifying the headers of the request your application is receiving. On each request that Slack sends out, they also attach an HTTP header, X-Slack-Signature. This signature is created by Slack using your Signing Secret key, and the full body of the request that they are sending back. Here is what Slack has to say about the Signing Secret key and information regarding it.</p>
<h2>What are signed secrets?</h2>
<blockquote>
<p>Slack creates a unique string for your app and shares it with you. Verify requests from Slack with confidence by verifying signatures using your signing secret.</p>
<p>On each HTTP request that Slack sends, we add an X-Slack-Signature HTTP header. The signature is created by combining the signing secret with the body of the request we're sending using a standard HMAC-SHA256 keyed hash.</p>
<p>The resulting signature is unique to each request and doesn't directly contain any secret information. That keeps your app secure, preventing bad actors from causing mischief.</p>
<p>Signing secrets replace the old verification tokens. Good news: the new signature is used exactly the same way as the deprecated verification token. It's just computed more securely.</p>
<p>Some SDKs perform signature verification automatically, accessible via an easy drop-in replacement of your signing secret for your old verification token. See the SDK support section for more detail.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Well, now you can see why I said it was indeed a rookie mistake by not including it the first time. So, I went to make a middleware, which of course, Laravel, makes this painless.</p>
<p>I looked and didn't see an example for PHP; however, from the documentation of Slack, it didn't look too hard to complete. So I started my way making the middleware and came up with the following.</p>
<h2>The Code</h2>
<pre><code class="language-php">&lt;?php

namespace App\Http\Middleware;

use App\Exceptions\SlackHashMismtachException;
use App\Exceptions\SlackHeadersMissingException;
use Closure;

class VerifyRequestIsFromSlack
{
    /**
     * @param $request
     * @param Closure $next
     * @return mixed
     * @throws SlackHashMismtachException
     * @throws SlackHeadersMissingException
     */
    public function handle($request, Closure $next)
    {
        if (!$request-&gt;headers-&gt;has('X-Slack-Signature') || !$request-&gt;headers-&gt;has('X-Slack-Request-Timestamp')) {
            throw new SlackHeadersMissingException("Invaid HTTP headers.");
        }

        $version = explode('=', $request-&gt;header('X-Slack-Signature'));
        $timestamp = $request-&gt;header('X-Slack-Request-Timestamp');

        $slackSignature = "{$version[0]}:$timestamp:{$request-&gt;getContent()}";

        $slackHashedSignature = hash_hmac('sha256', $slackSignature, 'xxxxxxxSigningSecretxxxxxxxxx');

        if (!hash_equals($request-&gt;header('X-Slack-Signature'), "v0=$slackHashedSignature")) {
            throw new SlackHashMismtachException("Whoops, looks like that hash doesn't match");
        }

        return $next($request);
    }
}</code></pre>
<p>In the above, we simply check if the HTTP headers for Slack exists; if the X-Slack-Signature or the X-Slack-Request-Timestamp is missing, we throw a custom exception. Of course, throwing a generic exception would also work. Thereafter, we simply grab the version from the X-Slack-Signature, X-Slack-Request-Timestamp.</p>
<p>Once I had that information, I passed that information into the hash_hmac function within PHP. Along with the body of the request untouched. After doing this, it is time to verify the hash that was just created to the hash that was sent in the X-Slack-Signature. If the hashes don't match we again throw a custom exception, and if it does we continue and the request is fulfilled reached out Route, in Laravel to complete the request and therefor show the Modal.</p>
<p>I will say, that I'm very much still learning about Slack and the API that it allows us to use. Any other information that I find that may be helpful, I will for sure blog about it and share that new-found knowledge that I discovered.</p>
<p>I may also work on getting a Slack package for Laravel to build out Modals, but at the present time, I don't have any plans for that just yet.</p>    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>/blog/stop-being-a-boss-be-a-leader</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="/blog/stop-being-a-boss-be-a-leader" />
    <title>Stop being a boss, be a leader</title>
    <published>2020-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-02-11T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Jason Kenyon</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">So wait, you are saying that I shouldn&#039;t be a boss? What do you even mean by this? Being a leader is being a boss but with diverse leadership practices. 
You aren&#039;t bossing or commanding, neither pointing fingers. A boss uses words such as I, me,......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <h3>Being a Leader is Better Than a Boss</h3>
<p>So wait, you are saying that I shouldn't be a boss? What do you even mean by this? Being a leader is being a boss but with diverse leadership practices. </p>
<p>You aren't bossing or commanding, neither pointing fingers. A boss uses words such as I, me, myself... </p>
<p>A leader will use words such as we, us. A boss will have issues with keeping people under them. Where a leader will have people stay, thrive, gain respect for those below them. </p>
<blockquote>
<h4>Employees don't drop companies they leave managers/supervisors.</h4>
</blockquote>
<h3>Why You Should Strive To Be a Leader</h3>
<p>Being a leader is so much more influential than being a boss! You challenge yourself to teach, encourage, guide people out of their comfort zone. You take the time to develop them and offer a helping hand when things get rocky. A boss is someone that will push paper and do what is best for them, moreover not necessarily what is suitable for the morale of the company. </p>
<p>Is being a boss a bad thing? This depends on how you take your power of being a boss. While I'm a supervisor, I'm the supervisor of various people under me. However, I don't relate to myself as their boss but as their leader. </p>
<p>You see each person that is under me is someone! That someone has vulnerabilities and strengths. It is my responsibility to discover these vulnerabilities and strengths. Help them grow as a person, and as an employee within the organization. </p>
<p>At the end, when you are a leader you are guaranteeing that the company will be thriving because more people will stay. People don't get frustrated by the company, they get weary of their bosses, and how they get treated. </p>
<p>What prompted me to even write this post. Was a inspring YouTube video, the video creator makes a great point and asks a great question.</p>
<blockquote>
<h4>Sir, ask yourself this question... Have you ever heard of a &quot;World Boss&quot;?</h4>
</blockquote>
<p>I recommend anyone that is reading this to take the time and watch the video. The message in the video is powerful, encouraging.</p>
<p>Something that we as leaders or even employees should follow. You can find that video at <strong><a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=LrVNTZ6ORm8" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Boss vs Employee (2020) </a></strong></p>
<h3>Dealing with Performance Management</h3>
<p>So, this will bring the subjects of so we shouldn't issue performance administration. Furthermore, be our employees' friends. The answer to this is simple!</p>
<p>Performance management is in place to provide that feedback to the employee. To coach and develop them. An employee will thrive for feedback if provided with care.</p>
<p>As a leader, you have to find the balance of providing it. By the time performance management is needed. The employee should know what you have done to help them.</p>
<p>They will also see and understand that performance management is coming. As you took the time to develop and extend a hand to help them out. </p>
<blockquote>
<p><strong><em>The Opinions Expressed In This Post Are My Own and How I View Things in a Position That I am In.</em></strong></p>
</blockquote>    ]]></content>
</entry>
            <entry>
    <id>/blog/first-post-on-the-blog</id>
    <link type="text/html" rel="alternate" href="/blog/first-post-on-the-blog" />
    <title>First post on the blog</title>
    <published>2020-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</published>
    <updated>2020-02-10T00:00:00+00:00</updated>
    <author>
        <name>Jason Kenyon</name>
    </author>
    <summary type="html">Hi, I&#039;m Jason! Welcome to my first blog post.
Recently, blogs have become a great source and an abundance of knowledge. I wanted to present the sources of information that I have also come across and experienced.
So, welcome to my brand-new website; I......</summary>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[
        <p>Hi, I'm Jason! Welcome to my first blog post.</p>
<p>Recently, blogs have become a great source and an abundance of knowledge. I wanted to present the sources of information that I have also come across and experienced.</p>
<p>So, welcome to my brand-new website; I intend on blogging about programming, life, and what else may come to mind. I also want to write about what I've learned from the Laravel community. I'm also establishing a place to allow me to provide and yield tutorials, and overall a database of information I can look back on.</p>
<p>So if you're ready, we will go ahead and dive into it. I wanted to start my first post by providing information on what I made the website on. I also thought that it was a great time to give readers that will visit my site, a bit more information about me. It allows you to know who is behind the scenes and writing these blog posts. Though that is always the troublesome part right... What should I start with? I guess I will present a bit more information about myself so that you know who is writing these blog posts.</p>
<h3>A Bit More About Jason</h3>
<p>I'm an uncomplicated man that enjoys learning new things and teaching. I live in <strong>Newport News, Virginia</strong>. With my beautiful wife, who happens to also run her own business, <a href="https://preciousmemories.photography" target="_blank" rel="noopener">PreciousMemories Photography</a>. Running a business with her has been an eye-opening adventure! I didn't understand how much work is involved in trying to create and run a business.</p>
<p>Between the two of us, we have 6 kids together; I have three girls and two boys that I couldn't be more delighted about. I'm also a stepfather of her son but at the end of the day... Do we need to put stepfather into something? I have always thought that blood doesn't define your family. The love and connection that you have with each other.</p>
<h3>The Road to Static Site Generators that Didn't Work Out.</h3>
<p>Okay, okay I get it you are ready for the nuts and bolts that run this website. Well, I began making the website in a mixture of things. One of which I began to write it in was Laravel. It's a PHP framework that I absolutely appreciate, and want to use it on all projects. Though, of course, we all know that each project has its own requirements. Building it with <a href="https://laravel.com" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Laravel</a> was sequentially going to be overkill.</p>
<p>I didn't want to use WordPress. It's a good firm blogging platform, though their vision has gone away from being just that. A blogging platform to a full-blown CMS. It tries too hard to be a CMS, and genuinely, the core isn't too bad? (pun intended) The issue is plugins and themes that you can get for it. Neglecting to patch things, and always trying to keep plugins/themes updated. People also tend to overdo it with plugins making their website slow. Not that WordPress by default isn't slow already... I wanted something that was going to be fast, simple, and easy to update.</p>
<p>Static sites here I come! So I went on the look for finding the most suitable static site generator that I could find. Though we know this is a user preference.</p>
<p>I started working with <a href="https://www.gatsbyjs.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gatsby</a>, it was solid and felt great. I was also using Contentful as the backend after I found a post on <a href="https://medium.com/ryanwiemer/gatsby-and-the-jam-stack-91e31508f364" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Medium</a> from Ryan Wiemer. After a couple of weeks of development. It just felt <strong>overly-complicated</strong>... I thought about maintenance, do I want to rely that much on javascript?</p>
<p>I then found <a href="https://gridsome.org/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Gridsome</a>, <em>yes, okay I know it's also javascript and built using <strong>Vuejs</strong> rather than <strong>Reactjs</strong>.</em> So, I started playing with Gridsome, and naturally, to be quite outspoken, I truly <em>valued</em> it over Gatsby. It was something that I knew and was familiar with. After all, I come from the Laravel community, where Vuejs is a notable player.</p>
<p>Everything was coming together, and I completed and launched the site with Netlify. Though, after a while, it still felt like something was yearning, or I was <strong>overloading</strong> it with <em>javascript</em>. So I had begun the hunt once again for something that may work out better.</p>
<h3>Jigsaw by TightenCo That Lead a Clear Path</h3>
<p>I eventually came across and settled on <a href="https://jigsaw.tighten.co/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Jigsaw</a>, by TigtenCo. Accurately, I couldn't be more fulfilled with how things worked out. They have an astonishing <a href="https://github.com/tightenco/jigsaw-blog-template" target="_blank" rel="noopener">blog template</a> to start from. Which is being used right now with just edits to make it my style, on this very website!</p>
<p>All the blog posts are all done and wrote in Markdown, heck even my <a href="https://jasonkenyon.me/uses" target="_blank" rel="noopener">uses</a> page is done in Markdown! Which is just exceptional and robust enough so that I don't have to write a single line more of HTML. The CSS framework used is none other than <a href="https://tailwindcss.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener">TailwindCSS</a>. Which if you have not heard of it, or even tried it. I can't encourage you enough to, just stop reading this and try it out! It is an astounding CSS framework.</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Tailwind is different.</p>
<p>Instead of unreasonable predesigned components, Tailwind provides low-level utility classes that let you build completely custom designs without ever leaving your HTML.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>Though, if I ought to be genuine about what I prefer the most notable about <strong>Jigsaw</strong>, it would come down to just being able to use <a href="https://laravel.com/docs/master/blade" target="_blank" rel="noopener">Laravel's blade</a> templating. With the duo pack that is running now, I just feel overly satisfied with how things have come together. I will genuinely continue to use Jigsaw. It is just dead simple and easy to use and makes making static websites an easy task.</p>
<p>Overall, I'm still learning more and more about <strong>Jigsaw</strong>. I will continue to blog about my experience with it and post new updates on things that I'm working on. Any releases or new erudition that I think everyone will enjoy.</p>
<p>Until next time, stay searching and learning, and getting it!</p>    ]]></content>
</entry>
    </feed>
